<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rasyidhakim.com</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/</link><description>Recent content on rasyidhakim.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:38:49 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://rasyidhakim.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Streaming Platform</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/data-streaming-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/data-streaming-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In an organization that heavily adopts Apache Kafka and event-driven architecture, Kafka events become a critical asset — enabling the development of various applications that react to real-time data.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Clickstream Ingestion</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/clickstream-ingestion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/clickstream-ingestion/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Clickstream data is essential for marketing analytics and product development. However, collecting and managing this data presents several challenges. The ingestion system must be scalable to handle the high volume of user-generated events. It must also support flexible schemas to accommodate variations across event types. Additionally, the high frequency of incoming data requires careful selection of the communication protocol to ensure efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Customer Segmentation Engine</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/customer-segmentation-engine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/customer-segmentation-engine/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Being able to define customer segments based on user behavior and attributes is essential for effective marketing. Traditionally, creating these segments requires marketers to identify data sources, write SQL queries, and manually execute them — a process that is tedious, error-prone, and time-consuming.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Clickstream Analytics Redesign</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/clickstream-analytics-redesign/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/clickstream-analytics-redesign/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;An internal platform was developed to support analytics on top of clickstream data, primarily for product analytics. It allowed users to visualize trends, build dashboards, browse a catalog of clickstream events, and trace individual user activity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A/B Testing Platform</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/a-b-testing-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/a-b-testing-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A/B testing allows product teams to optimize experiences based on data rather than assumptions. To enable this, an internal A/B testing platform was developed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tightening the Frontend Feedback Loop With Browser Aware Agents</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/tightening-the-frontend-feedback-loop-with-browser-aware-agents/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:38:49 +0700</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/tightening-the-frontend-feedback-loop-with-browser-aware-agents/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;My initial &lt;strong&gt;frontend&lt;/strong&gt; workflow was functional but tedious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d discuss frontend design in ChatGPT, take screenshots, send them back, then hand things off to an agent to implement.
It worked, but every iteration felt slower than it should have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point I stopped and thought: what if the agent could actually see the browser?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That question led me to &lt;strong&gt;chrome-devtools-mcp&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the agent had visibility into the live DOM, styles, and runtime behavior, the workflow simplified.
Design and implementation collapsed into a single loop.
No more screenshot ping-pong.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Skills Drift Problem</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/skills-drift-problem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:01:11 +0700</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/skills-drift-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A quick lesson from sharing skills across coding agents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you work across multiple projects, your skills decay faster than your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept copy-pasting the same skills across repos and agent-specific directories. Each project slowly drifted. Small tweaks here, forgotten updates there. I never knew which version was the real one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem showed up quickly, so I fixed it at the root.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution I landed on was simple: centralize skills and sync them across projects. I built a small CLI to support that workflow, with a single source of truth and on-demand updates.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Some Coding Agents Just Work</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/why-some-coding-agents-just-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:35:49 +0700</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/why-some-coding-agents-just-work/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks, I’ve been working with coding agents for my development workflows, mainly Kilo Code and Codex. I came into Codex after spending significant time with Kilo, so the contrast was immediately noticeable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kilo felt smooth out of the box. Codex felt more erratic. My first instinct was to judge the agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking closer, the difference wasn’t model capability. It was defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kilo ships Distinct modes for different tasks (ask, architect, debug, code)
-Strong context and task scaffolding by default
-Built-in agent tools like a browser&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>When does expertise turn into value?</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/when-does-expertise-turn-into-value/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 05:42:09 +0700</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/when-does-expertise-turn-into-value/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Stepping away from a highly technical role in a large corporation pulled me out of the comfort of clean abstractions and into the messy reality of how industries actually work. Beneath the surface, every industry is a web of interconnected value chains, each shaped by geography and culture. What works in Jakarta doesn’t necessarily resonate in New York. What succeeds in New York might feel irrelevant in Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re equipped with technical expertise, you understand how things work. That depth creates a bias toward selling the how of the building. Consultancies or agencies that trade on execution. But what kind of service you can offer, and how it’s perceived, depends on where you operate in the chain. The same skill can be indispensable in one context and invisible in another.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>