<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on rasyidhakim.com</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on rasyidhakim.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:35:49 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Some Coding Agents Just Work</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/why-some-coding-agents-just-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 12:35:49 +0700</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/why-some-coding-agents-just-work/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks, I’ve been working with coding agents for my development workflows, mainly Kilo Code and Codex. I came into Codex after spending significant time with Kilo, so the contrast was immediately noticeable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kilo felt smooth out of the box. Codex felt more erratic. My first instinct was to judge the agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking closer, the difference wasn’t model capability. It was defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kilo ships Distinct modes for different tasks (ask, architect, debug, code)
-Strong context and task scaffolding by default
-Built-in agent tools like a browser&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>When does expertise turn into value?</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/when-does-expertise-turn-into-value/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 05:42:09 +0700</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/blog/when-does-expertise-turn-into-value/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Stepping away from a highly technical role in a large corporation pulled me out of the comfort of clean abstractions and into the messy reality of how industries actually work. Beneath the surface, every industry is a web of interconnected value chains, each shaped by geography and culture. What works in Jakarta doesn’t necessarily resonate in New York. What succeeds in New York might feel irrelevant in Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re equipped with technical expertise, you understand how things work. That depth creates a bias toward selling the how of the building. Consultancies or agencies that trade on execution. But what kind of service you can offer, and how it’s perceived, depends on where you operate in the chain. The same skill can be indispensable in one context and invisible in another.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>