<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portfolio on rasyidhakim.com</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content in Portfolio on rasyidhakim.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Streaming Platform</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/data-streaming-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/data-streaming-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In an organization that heavily adopts Apache Kafka and event-driven architecture, Kafka events become a critical asset — enabling the development of various applications that react to real-time data.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Clickstream Ingestion</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/clickstream-ingestion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/clickstream-ingestion/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Clickstream data is essential for marketing analytics and product development. However, collecting and managing this data presents several challenges. The ingestion system must be scalable to handle the high volume of user-generated events. It must also support flexible schemas to accommodate variations across event types. Additionally, the high frequency of incoming data requires careful selection of the communication protocol to ensure efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Customer Segmentation Engine</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/customer-segmentation-engine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/customer-segmentation-engine/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Being able to define customer segments based on user behavior and attributes is essential for effective marketing. Traditionally, creating these segments requires marketers to identify data sources, write SQL queries, and manually execute them — a process that is tedious, error-prone, and time-consuming.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Clickstream Analytics Redesign</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/clickstream-analytics-redesign/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/clickstream-analytics-redesign/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;An internal platform was developed to support analytics on top of clickstream data, primarily for product analytics. It allowed users to visualize trends, build dashboards, browse a catalog of clickstream events, and trace individual user activity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A/B Testing Platform</title><link>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/a-b-testing-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://rasyidhakim.com/portfolio/a-b-testing-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A/B testing allows product teams to optimize experiences based on data rather than assumptions. To enable this, an internal A/B testing platform was developed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>